When things get bad, they'll do their worst.
Guardians of the Galaxy is a action, science fiction,
adventure film directed by James Gunn.
Light years from Earth, 26 years after being abducted, Peter Quill finds himself the prime
target of a manhunt after discovering an orb wanted by Ronan the Accuser.
Peter Quill, played by Chris Pratt.
Gamora, played by Zoe Saldaña.
Drax, played by Dave Bautista.
Groot (voice), played by Vin Diesel.
Rocket (voice), played by Bradley Cooper.
Ronan, played by Lee Pace.
Guardians of the Galaxy (retroactively referred to
as Guardians of the Galaxy Vol.
1) is a 2014 American superhero film based on the Marvel
Comics superhero team of the same name.
Produced by Marvel Studios and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion
Pictures, it is the 10th film in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU).
Directed by James Gunn, who wrote the screenplay with Nicole Perlman, it features an ensemble cast including Chris Pratt, Zoe Saldaña, Dave Bautista,
Vin Diesel, and Bradley Cooper as the titular Guardians, along with Lee Pace, Michael Rooker, Karen Gillan, Djimon Hounsou, John C.
Reilly, Glenn Close, and Benicio del Toro.
In the film, Peter Quill (Pratt) and a group of extraterrestrial
criminals go on the run after stealing a powerful artifact.
Perlman began working on the screenplay in 2009.
Producer Kevin Feige first publicly mentioned Guardians of the Galaxy as a potential film in 2010 and
Marvel Studios announced it was in active development at the July 2012 San Diego Comic-Con.
Gunn was hired to write and direct the film that September.
In February 2013, Pratt was hired to play Peter Quill / Star-Lord, and
the supporting cast members were subsequently confirmed.
Principal photography began in July 2013 at Shepperton Studios in England, with
filming continuing in London before wrapping in October 2013.
In addition to an original score by Tyler Bates, the soundtrack includes
several popular songs from the 1960s and 1970s chosen by Gunn.
Post-production was completed on July 7, 2014.
Guardians of the Galaxy premiered at the Dolby Theatre in Hollywood, Los Angeles, on July 21, 2014, and
was theatrically released in the United States on August 1 as part of Phase Two of the MCU.
It was a critical and commercial success, grossing $773.3 million
worldwide and became the third-highest-grossing film of 2014.
It was praised for its screenplay, direction, acting, humor,
soundtrack, visual effects and action sequences.
It was nominated for two awards at the 87th Academy
Awards, and received numerous other accolades.
Two sequels have been released: Guardians of the Galaxy Vol.
2 (2017) and Guardians of the Galaxy Vol.
The film explores themes of spacecraft, based on
comic, space, orphan, adventurer.
The tone is thought_provoking.